<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Observability on Elastic Observability on AWS Workshop</title>
    <link>/99_observability.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Observability on Elastic Observability on AWS Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/99_observability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Observe the AWS platform</title>
      <link>/99_observability/page-1-platform.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/99_observability/page-1-platform.html</guid>
      <description>Platform Logs In AWS you have three options to collect logs. This also holds for the platform / service specific logs. You can collect the data via the Serverless Log forwarder, via CloudWatch or collect the data from an S3 bucket.
If you decide for the S3 bucket you need to configure SQS notifications that get triggered whenever new data is written to the bucket. This approach is best practice to avoid significant lagging with polling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observe apps running in AWS</title>
      <link>/99_observability/page-1-example-app.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/99_observability/page-1-example-app.html</guid>
      <description>While apps running in AWS use many of the available AWS services they all have their custom code as well. Consequently observing the AWS services and platform is only one part of the story. The other necessary part to get full visibility is to have the ability to look deep into what&amp;rsquo;s happening in your application as well by observing your individual logs, metrics and application traces.
Application logs In order to get your individual logs to Elastic you need to consider two things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observe apps running in Kubernetes (EKS)</title>
      <link>/99_observability/page-1-k8s.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/99_observability/page-1-k8s.html</guid>
      <description>Observe apps running in Kubernetes (EKS) This guide will cover how to use the Elastic Stack to provide comprehensive monitoring of your EKS Kubernetes environment including:
Container Logging Container Metrics Kubernetes posture management Kubernetes process and session monitoring EKS Audit Logging Kubernetes SIEM rules To be able to tell the Elastic Agent what data to collect we will create a policy with the relevant kubernetes integrations.
In the left navigation menu, select “Fleet” Select the “Agent policies” tab Select “Create agent policy” Call the policy something like “k8s” and leave the default to gather system logs and metrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observe vulnerabilities and compliance</title>
      <link>/99_observability/page-1-conpliance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/99_observability/page-1-conpliance.html</guid>
      <description>Observing vulnerabilities and compliance Operating your services within AWS enables you to use the wide range of AWS specific offerings in your application. Because of the complexity and the many different configuration options as well as the shared responsibilities between AWS your company its also possible to operate with less secure setups.
In order to prevent that Elastic also offers to support you with observing the configurations of your used services.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
